# Kristen De La Rosa

## **Professional Summary**

I am a Web Developer transitioning from the Educational Professional setting. I am highly talented individual with strong analytical skills and a desire to work as a Jr. Web Developer. Hard-working and Self-motivated full stack developer with knowledge and proficiency in JavaScript, HTML, CSS, and mobile responsive web development, as well as strong skills and ability to learn new frameworks and communicate within teams. I have done work collaborating with talented people to create digital products demonstrating skills in both front and back-end development. I have worked on producing high quality responsive websites and exceptional user experience for further insight into my experience please visit:

GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/KristenDLR">https://github.com/KristenDLR</a> Portfolio: <a href="https://kristendlr.github.io/">https://github.com/KristenDLR</a>

#### 630 Benowe Scotia Road, Glendale, CA 91207 (609) 865-5130 Delarosa.kristen@gmail.com LinkedIN:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/kris10-de-la-rosa/

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Trilogy Education- Full Stack Web Development Program**-SeniorLearning Assistant

June 2021 – PRESENT

- Subject Matter Expert
- Solve for and respond to technical, conceptual, and general based challenges with world-class student support.
- Articulate clear and thorough responses that support debugging needs.
- Oversees testing and develops fixes.
- Coordinate schedules and Mentor junior staff

## Rutgers University Full-stack Bootcamp, NJ— Teaching Assistant

March 2020 – November 2021

- Oversaw the review code, and guide activity-based workshops
- Organized Teaching Materials
- Coordinates review of key full-stack concepts
- Facilitate debugging
- Demonstrate instructional skills
- Support students through exercises designed to embed key web development concepts
- Promote a dynamic and collaborative coding environment
- Initiates professional growth by keeping up to date on relevant trends in the web development field

### **Livingston Public Schools** — High School History Teacher

2017 — July 2021

- Communicated clear learning objectives to students on each unique chapter.
- Attended professional development seminars and workshops to maintain expertise in innovative teaching methods.
- Maintained regular verbal and written communication with school counselors and parents to update with student progress, class schedules and important test dates.
- Provided advice and guidance to students needing morale-boosting and academic advising.
- Pioneered the implementation of different technologies such as Technology-based assignments and student response systems to engage students in class instruction and diversify approaches.

#### **Skills and Languages**

- HTML
- CSS
- DOM Manipulation
- JavaScript
- jQuery
- React
- AJAX
- Node.js
- Problem-Solving
- Presentations
- MySQL
- MongoDB
- API Framework
- Responsive Design
- Testing/ Debugging

#### **EDUCATION**

### Coding Bootcamp, Full-stack Web Development, 2019 Rutgers University

- Full Stack: Front and Backend Development
- Relevant Coursework Completed: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, React, MySQL, MongoDB, Node, Yarn, Handlebars.js, Cheerio, Firebase, API Framework, Animation, GitHub

# **Bachelor of Arts, History and Education, 2010** King's College

- GPA: 3.37
- Honorable Mention
- History Honor Society, Phi Alpha Theta President
- Dean's List

#### **ACTIVITIES**

Volunteer Front End Coder, Hack for LA Project 311-data